You can create timed promotional offers with Amazon deals, an invite-only program that helps you
offer discounts to customers on eligible ASINs.
There are two types of deals available in the
Amazon store, Lightning Deals and Best deals.
Lightning deals run for 4 to 12 hours and are
ideal when you want to create urgency and drive quick sales with a deep discount.
They work best
for clearing excess inventory and selling seasonal products.
Best deals run for a limited
number of days or throughout an entire high-velocity event.
These are best suited for
products where you have enough inventory to run a longer promotion and for seasonal items
that benefit from more visibility.
Access the deals dashboard to get started.
If this is
your first deal, you'll see the deals benefits page.
Select Create a New Deal to access the
dashboard.
Use the search and filtering options and select View on current or past deals to
review performance metrics and deal details.
To create a new deal, select Create a New Deal.
Here, eligible ASINs are displayed automatically.
ASIN recommendations are generated on a weekly
basis.
If you don't have active ASIN recommendations for deals, consider other promotion types,
such as price discounts or coupons.
Review the Amazon deals help page to see deal eligibility
requirements.
You can choose whether you would like to create deals one by one or in bulk.
To create deals in bulk, select Download All Recommendations for up to 1,500 ASIN recommendations
or use filters to select specific ASINs.
Then select Download Recommendations.
You'll
be redirected to the Manage in Bulk page where you can track the status of bulk recommendations.
Note, template processing may take up to 30 minutes.
Select Download File from the Downloads
tab under Recent Activities.
Complete the spreadsheet template, reviewing the instructions
on the Instructions tab.
In the Deal Recommendation Template tab, input the deal schedule, review
offer price, and additional required fields for each Amazon store.
Once your template is
complete, save the file, then select Upload File from the Manage in Bulk tool.
If any
issues are detected while uploading, re-download the Recommendation file and go to the Error
Sheet tab.
Here, you can find a list of the errors made in the previously uploaded file.
The errors can also be spotted in the Deal Recommendation Template tab.
Once the errors
are fixed, re-upload the file to continue your deal creation.
To create deals one by one, use the search or filtering options to locate eligible ASINs
and choose Select.
Select the Amazon stores and audience you want your deal to be eligible
for.
Next, select a schedule for your deal.
You will see a list of available weeks that
your deal can run.
Review the fee for your deal.
Fees may change based on several factors,
such as timing.
Finally, configure your deal, selecting any eligible product variations
of this ASIN that you want to include.
We recommend including as many variations as possible.
Set offer prices and discounts and adjust committed units if required.
Select a featured
ASIN for your deal.
Review each section for accuracy, then click Submit Deal to submit
the deal for review.
Go to the deals dashboard in Seller Central to get started.
For additional
guidance, visit the Create a Deal Help page.